Nobody is beyond redemption.
The Three Burials of Melquiades Estrada is a adventure,
crime, drama film directed by Tommy Lee Jones.
When brash Texas border officer Mike Norton wrongfully kills and buries the friend and ranch hand of Pete Perkins, the
latter is reminded of a promise he made to bury his friend, Melquiades Estrada, in his Mexican home town.
He kidnaps Norton and exhumes Estrada's corpse, and the odd
caravan sets out on horseback for Mexico.
Pete Perkins, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Mike Norton, played by Barry Pepper.
Sheriff Frank Belmont, played by Dwight Yoakam.
Lou Ann Norton, played by January Jones.
Rachel, played by Melissa Leo.
Melquiades Estrada, played by Julio Cesar Cedillo.
The Three Burials of Melquiades Estrada (also known as Three Burials) is a 2005 neo-Western film directed by
and starring Tommy Lee Jones (in his directorial debut) and written by Guillermo Arriaga.
It also stars Barry Pepper, Julio Cedillo, Dwight Yoakam, and January Jones.
The film was inspired by the real-life killing in Texas of a teenager, Esequiel Hernandez Jr, by United States Marines during a military operation near the United
States–Mexico border as well as the novel As I Lay Dying by William Faulkner, which contains the same plot premise and challenges encountered in the film.
The film has many flashbacks with the same event
shown from different perspectives.
The film explores themes of mexico, texas, illegal
immigration, border patrol, usa–mexico border.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.